[[{"question":"Which of the following answers is NOT true about the Canada/USA relationship?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canada/USA relationship is the closest and the most extensive in the worlD."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada and the USA are the largest trading partners in the worlD."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada exports very few goods to the USA."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada and the USA share the longest undefended international border."}]},{"question":"What does the Crown mean for Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown is the symbol of the national motto, A Mari Usque Ad Mare, which, in Latin, means ‘from sea to sea.'"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown reflects the Greco-Roman heritage of Western civilization in which democracy originateD."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown is the symbol of England, France, Scotland, and Ireland, as well as red maple leaves."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Crown is a symbol of government, including Parliament, legislatures, courts, police services, and the armed forces."}]},{"question":"Who governs Canada on a daily basis at the federal level?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Governor General"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier"}]},{"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Guy Carleton"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Isaac Brock"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's system of governance?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Federal state, parliamentary democracy, and constitutional monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Police state, parliamentary democracy, and constitutional monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal state, provincial state, and constitutional monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal state, parliamentary democracy, and dictatorship"}]},{"question":"What region of Canada is known as the \"Land of the Midnight Sun?\"","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Northern territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Atlantic provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Western provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prairie provinces"}]},{"question":"Under Canadian law, why is every person presumed to be innocent until proven guilty?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To establish that no person or group is above the law."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To guarantee due legal process under the law."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To ensure that men and women are equal under the law."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To provide freedom of thought, belief, opinion, and expression."}]},{"question":"Which of the following were the first four provinces in the Canadian Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba, Nova Scotia, and Province of Canada (Ontario & Quebec)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"New Brunswick, Nova Scotia, and Province of Canada (Ontario & Quebec)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick, Newfoundland, and Province of Canada (Ontario & Quebec)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick, Nova Scotia, Alberta, and Manitoba"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of hockey?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the national summer sport."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the most popular spectator sport in Canada and is also its national winter sport."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada won a gold medal in 2008's Olympics in this event."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"}]},{"question":"Which animal is the national symbol of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Beaver"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Deer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Cougar"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Bear"}]},{"question":"What does the National Register of Electors contain?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The names of Canadian tax payers"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The names of landed immigrants"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The names of all Canadian citizens"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The names of Canadian citizens at least 18 years of age who are qualified to vote in federal elections and referendums"}]},{"question":"What is the highest honour a Canadian can receive?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Cross"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Order of Peace"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Victoria Cross"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Crown"}]},{"question":"Why was the discovery of insulin by Canadians so important?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Insulin has eliminated polio in the worlD."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Insulin controls human growth hormones, which has made life better for millions of people."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Insulin treats heart disorders, which has saved millions of lives worldwide."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Insulin treats diabetes, which has saved millions of lives worldwide."}]},{"question":"Which Canadian province is the largest producer of oil and natural gas?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are Atlantic provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, and Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland, Nova Scotia, Manitoba, and Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, and Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Newfoundland, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, and Prince Edward Island"}]},{"question":"A Member of Parliament from Toronto decides to spend the weekend in his or her electoral district. This means the MP will be","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Somewhere in the USA"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Ottawa"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In the part of Toronto where the MP was elected"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Taking a tour in the province of Ontario"}]},{"question":"What is the primary role of the police in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To resolve disputes and interpret law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To provide national security intelligence to the government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To conduct or support land warfare, peacekeeping, or humanitarian missions"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To keep people safe and to enforce the law"}]},{"question":"Which of the following criterion gives a Canadian the right to vote?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Being on the official voters' list"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Being an immigrant"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Owning a house"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Having a driver's license"}]},{"question":"To which of the following communities do the majority of Canadians belong?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jewish"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hindu"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Muslim"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Christian"}]},{"question":"Of the following, what is a non-Canadian not allowed to do?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Own a house or a farm"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Get a higher education"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Vote in federal and provincial elections"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Get health insurance"}]},{"question":"Who out of the following is above the law in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No one"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Politicians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Judges"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Police"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of the Quebec Act of 1774?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Province of Quebec was divided into Upper Canada and Lower CanadA."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada's tolerance towards all religions was affecteD."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Peace, Order and Good Government became Canada's main principles."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the birth of CanadA."}]},{"question":"What principles out of the following is Canada's constitution based on?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Multiculturalism, Peace, and Order"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"War, Order, and Good Government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mobility Rights, Order, and Good Government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Peace, Order, and Good Government"}]},{"question":"What did the Suffrage Movement achieve?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Employment insurance was establisheD."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Women obtained the right to vote."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Slavery was abolished CanadA."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec experienced an era of rapid change."}]},{"question":"What are the three branches of the Canadian government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Executive, Legislative, and Monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Executive, Senate, and Judicial"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Executive, Police, and Judicial"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Executive, Legislative, and Judicial"}]}],[{"question":"Which of the following best describes the role of the Queen in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To run the federal government departments"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To peacefully oppose or try to improve government proposals"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To focus on citizenship and allegiance, be a symbol of Canadian sovereignty, and a guardian of constitutional freedoms"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To make important decisions about how the country is governed"}]},{"question":"Why is the War of 1812 significant to Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"More than 600,000 Canadians served in the war."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The war ensured that Canada would remain independent of the United States."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"North America was divided by the war."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"More than two-thirds of Acadians were deported from their homeland because of the war."}]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a responsibility of Canadian citizens?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Voting in elections"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Learning to speak both official languages"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Taking responsibility for oneself and one's family"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Obeying the law"}]},{"question":"What does the Canadian Crown symbolize?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Crown symbolizes that Canada is a constitutional monarchy."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown symbolizes the motto A Mari Usque Ad Mare."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown symbolizes England, France, Scotland, and Ireland."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown symbolizes the RCMP, the national police force of Canada."}]},{"question":"Which Canadian province has the largest population?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of a constitutional monarchy?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A constitutional monarchy is a form of government which is headed by a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King), who reigns in accordance with the Constitution"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A constitutional monarchy is a form of government in which a Monarch makes every decision regarding the way the country is ruled."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A constitutional monarchy is a form of government based on the principals of freedom of conscience and religion"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A constitutional monarchy is a form of government based on freedom of association"}]},{"question":"How are Members of Parliament chosen?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are chosen by the provincial Premiers."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They are elected by voters in their local constituency (riding)."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are elected by landowners and police chiefs."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are appointed by the Prime Minister."}]},{"question":"What is the main advantage of the NAFTA agreement?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Free trade among Canada, the USA, and the UK"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Free trade among Canada, the USA, and Mexico"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Free trade between Canada and China"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Free trade between Canada and Japan"}]},{"question":"What are the three parts of Parliament?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sovereign, House of Commons, and Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier, House of Commons, and Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sovereign, House of Commons, and MPs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sovereign, Police, and Senate"}]},{"question":"What does Confederation mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the time when United States Confederate soldiers came to invade Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the joining of provinces to make a new country"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the joining of communities to become a province"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the joining of suburbs to form a large city"}]},{"question":"Why was the Canadian Pacific Railway built?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It was built because Ottawa promised to build it when British Columbia agreed to join Canada."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was built to provide a spectacular tourist excursion across precipitous passes and bridges"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was built so British Columbia could handle the trade of goods worth billions of dollars all around the world"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was built so that immigrants could settle in Central Canada."}]},{"question":"Miriam is a new immigrant in Canada. What law allows her to take up any job at par with a man?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Equal rights for men and women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Woman's superiority rights"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Woman's liberation rights"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New immigrant rights"}]},{"question":"What is a part of our heritage under the Canadian legal system?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Democratic principles and due process"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom under law"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Rule of law"}]},{"question":"In Federal elections, which of the following are elected?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Members of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Senators"}]},{"question":"Which eastern province in Canada has its own time zone?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Newfoundland & Labrador"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are the two fundamental freedoms under Canadian law?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Freedom of speech and freedom of religion"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom of speech and freedom of mobility"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom to buy a house and freedom of religion"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom to work anywhere and freedom of religion"}]},{"question":"Who is awarded the honor of Victoria Cross?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Only Canadian politicians"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A Canadian showing great bravery or self-sacrifice"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Only Police officers who have died in the line of duty"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian who has been elected Best Innovator of the Year"}]},{"question":"Why is the Battle of Vimy Ridge important to Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Japan surrendered in 1945 - the end of four years of war in the Pacific."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadians took part in the liberation of Italy in 1943-1944."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The valour and bravery of Canadian soldiers brought about a fantastic victory."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Royal Canadian Military saw its finest hour in the battle."}]},{"question":"Why is British Columbia known as Canada's Pacific Gateway?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the oldest colony of the British Empire and a strategic prize in Canada's early history."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Port of Vancouver handles billions of dollars in goods traded around the world."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It provides a spectacular tourist excursion across precipitous passes and bridges."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia is the largest producer of oil and gas."}]},{"question":"What do Canadians remember on Remembrance Day?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian victory in the Battle of Vimy Ridge"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sacrifices made by Canadian veterans and brave soldiers in wars"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian victory in World War I"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian victory in World War II"}]},{"question":"What is the role of the opposition parties?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To run the government as long as they have the support or confidence of the majority of the MPs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To make important decisions about how the country is governed"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To run the federal government departments"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To peacefully oppose or try to improve government proposals"}]},{"question":"Why is trade with other countries important to Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is important because trade brings prosperity and enables Canadians to enjoy one of the world's highest standards of living."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is important because Canada is a member of the World Trade Organization."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is important because French and Aboriginal people collaborated with Canada in the vast fur-trade economy."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is important because trade with other countries changed the way of life of the native peoples of Canada."}]},{"question":"Which of the following are Prairie Provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba, Ontario, and Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec, Saskatchewan, and Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba, Saskatchewan, and Yukon Territory"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Manitoba, Saskatchewan, and Alberta"}]},{"question":"What is the voting procedure in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Voting is completed by all of the above methods"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Voting is completed by Secret Ballots"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Voting is completed On-line"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Voting is completed by Open Ballots"}]},{"question":"The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms begins with which words?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The rights guaranteed in the Charter will not adversely affect any treaty or other rights or freedom of Aboriginal people."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadians can live and work anywhere they choose in Canada."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Whereas Canada is founded upon principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law..."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada! Our home and native land!"}]}],[{"question":"Who was the first leader of a responsible government in Canada in 1849?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jim Basally"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Sam Steele"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians served in the First World War?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About  1000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 240 000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"More than 80 000"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"More than 600 000"}]},{"question":"Who invented the sport of basketball?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Americans"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The French"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Germans"}]},{"question":"When does Canada celebrate Thanksgiving?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first Monday of September"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The second Monday of October"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first Monday of July"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first Friday of October"}]},{"question":"Where do most Inuit people live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"On reserve lands in Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the Prairie Provinces"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In scattered communities across the Arctic"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Ontario"}]},{"question":"What is celebrated on the 15th of February?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"National Flag of Canada Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Labour Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Vimy Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Family Day"}]},{"question":"What are the men who established Canada called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Fathers of Confederation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fathers of the Dominion of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fathers of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fathers of the Constitution"}]},{"question":"Which is Canada's largest city and main financial centre?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Toronto"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Calgary"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Vancouver"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Montreal"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"}]},{"question":"Who contributed to the invention of the radio and also sent one of the world's first wireless voice messages?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mike Lazaridis"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Reginald Fessenden"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mathew Evans"}]},{"question":"Who invented the snowmobile?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Emily Carr"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Louis Riel"}]},{"question":"How long does the appointment of Lieutenant Governor last?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"5 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"4 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"6 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"3 years"}]},{"question":"Which is the fundamental characteristic of Canadian heritage and identity?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian festivals"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Multiculturalism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French Culture"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English Culture"}]},{"question":"Who was the first French-Canadian Prime Minister?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir George-Étienne Cartier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John Alexander Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Wilfrid Laurier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Leonard Tilley"}]},{"question":"In which year did the British Parliament prohibit the buying and selling of slaves?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1807"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1793"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1877"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1833"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are two responsibilities of the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health care and education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defence and firefighting"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"National defence and foreign policy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Citizenship and maintaining highways"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a responsibility of the provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Navigation"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Municipal government"}]},{"question":"How many citizens of Canada served in the Second World War?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"2 million"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"11 million"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1 million"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"5 million"}]},{"question":"Which region was stormed and captured on D-Day (June 6, 1944) by the 3rd Canadian Infantry Division?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Paris"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"London"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Juno Beach"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Berlin"}]},{"question":"What should registered voters do if they do not receive a voter information card?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Call the local elections office"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Call the  taxation office"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Not vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Call the police"}]},{"question":"Use one of the following to complete this sentence: The House of Commons is a representative committee . . .","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"made up of members selected by the Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"appointed on the advice of the Governor General."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"appointed on the advice of the Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"made up of Members of Parliament elected by the people."}]},{"question":"What do Canadians normally wear on Remembrance Day?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A white shirt"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A black tie"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A red poppy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A green shirt"}]},{"question":"Which of the following describe two responsibilities of the provincial or territorial government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Policing and foreign policy"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Education and health care"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defence and highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Citizenship and firefighting"}]},{"question":"What is a voter information card?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A form that tells registered voters when and where to vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A form that tells registered voters  the province in which they may vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A form that indicates the candidates in an electoral district"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A form that indicates the nearest location in which to vote"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the highest court of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Provincial Court"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Supreme Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Small Claims Court"}]}],[{"question":"In the 1960s, Quebec experienced an era of rapid change. What is it called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Quiet Revolution"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The East Movement"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Suffrage Movement"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Francophonie"}]},{"question":"What is celebrated on April 9th?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Thanksgiving Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Boxing Day"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Vimy Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Family Day"}]},{"question":"The ancestors of the Aboriginals are believed to have migrated from which of the following continents?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Asia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Australia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Europe"}]},{"question":"Who invented the worldwide system of standard time zones?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Sandford Fleming"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Reginald Fessenden"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier"}]},{"question":"What is the fixed day for Canada's federal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The 3rd Monday in October, four years after the Election Day of the previous federal election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"There is no fixed day for Canada's federal elections."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"May 10th, six years after the previous federal election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 1st Monday in September, four years after the Election Day of the previous federal election."}]},{"question":"What is Canada's national winter sport?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lacrosse"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Golf"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Hockey"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basketball"}]},{"question":"What is celebrated on the 26th of December?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Remembrance Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Victoria Day"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Boxing Day"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's rank in the world in terms of geographical size?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the fourth-largest country in the world."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the smallest country in the world."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the third-largest country in the world."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the second-largest country in the world."}]},{"question":"Which sport has the greatest number of registered players in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basketball"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Soccer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lacrosse"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Curling"}]},{"question":"What is the symbol of the Canadian government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Crown"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Snowbirds"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The National Flag"}]},{"question":"How many provinces does Canada have?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"10"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"7"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"13"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"3"}]},{"question":"When was 'employment insurance' introduced by the Canadian federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1940"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1965"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1947"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1950"}]},{"question":"What types of jobs are provided by service industries?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Transportation and education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Communications and retail services"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All of these"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Tourism and government"}]},{"question":"Whose portrait is featured on the Canadian $10 bill?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Arthur Currie"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Frederic Banting"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir John Alexander MacDonald"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of the provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Foreign Policy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"}]},{"question":"What information can be found on a voter information card?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All of the above."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A voter information card indicates when and where a registered elector can vote in an election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A voter information card indicates which candidates are eligible in an election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A voter information card contains a list of registered electors."}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Property and Civil Rights"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hospitals"}]},{"question":"Which Canadian province has the largest population of Aboriginals?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Manitoba"}]},{"question":"When is Labour Day celebrated in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 1st of July"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 1st of May"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The 1st Monday of September"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 3rd Monday of October"}]},{"question":"How is Canada ranked in terms of geographical size in the world?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the largest country on Earth."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the second largest country on Earth."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the seventh largest country on Earth."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the smallest country on Earth."}]},{"question":"Since when has the protocol for the amendment of the Canadian Constitution existed?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1885"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1982"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1962"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1972"}]},{"question":"Who represents an electoral district?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Lieutenant Governor"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A Member of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commissioner"}]},{"question":"Which province is known as the 'Land of 100,000 Lakes'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"After a federal election, which party forms the new government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The party with the most elected representatives forms the new government."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen picks the party which will form the new government."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The elected Premiers of each province pick the party which will form the new government."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General proposes a law for the elected officials to choose the governing body which will form the new government."}]},{"question":"Which of the following was invented by Alexander Graham Bell?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fax machine"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Telephone"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"BlackBerry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Internet"}]}],[{"question":"What does the blindfolded Lady Justice symbolize?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The judicial system is founded on the presumption of innocence in criminal matters."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The judicial system is blind to all considerations other than facts."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The judicial system must respect all the legal rights to which a blind person is entitled under the law."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above."}]},{"question":"What is a political candidate?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A member of the Canadian Senate Committee"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A government employee"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A person who is registered to run for an office in an election"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A staff member of Elections Canada"}]},{"question":"Who was John Graves Simcoe?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Founder of the city of Victoria"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Founder of the city of Toronto"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Founder of the city of Kingston"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Founder of the city of Calgary"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of the sport lacrosse in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is Canada's official winter sport."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is Canada's official summer sport."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is Canada's most popular sport."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is fun game played on ice."}]},{"question":"What is significant about the fact that Canada and America share 'the world's longest undefended border'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It enables Canadians to enter the USA without needing identification."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It enables millions of Canadians and Americans to cross the border every year in with relative ease and safety."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It enables over three-quarters of Canadian exports to enter the USA every year without taxes or fees."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It enables Canada to export billions of dollars worth of energy products to the USA every year."}]},{"question":"To whom or what do Canadians profess loyalty?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To Geopolitical entities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To the Canadian Constitution"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To a person who represents all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To the Canadian Flag"}]},{"question":"How many territories does Canada have?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"13"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"7"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"10"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"3"}]},{"question":"What three requirements must a potential elector meet in order to vote in a federal election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A potential elector must be 21 years or older, must work for the government, and must be a landed immigrant in order to vote in a federal election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A potential elector must have a driver's license, must be 21 years or older, and must be registered on the voters' list in order to vote in a federal election."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A potential elector must be 18 years or older, must be a Canadian citizen, and must be registered on the voters' list in order to vote in a federal election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A potential elector must be a landed immigrant, must be 18 years or older, and must be registered on the voters' list in order to vote in a federal election."}]},{"question":"For which of the following is the federal government responsible?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Criminal law and citizenship"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Civil Rights"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health"}]},{"question":"When is 'Sir Wilfrid Laurier Day' celebrated?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"December 26th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"May 9th"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"November 20th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"November 21st"}]},{"question":"The discovery of insulin was a result of whose work?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Frederick Banting and Charles Best"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Dr. Emily Stowe"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"John Graves Simcoe"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Charles Best and Reginald Fessenden"}]},{"question":"For which of the following is the provincial government responsible?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Property and civil rights"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is Canada's only officially bilingual province?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"}]},{"question":"Quebec is Canada's main producer of which of the following?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Music"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Pulp and paper"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Processed foods"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Literary works"}]},{"question":"How often are federal elections held in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every seven years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every six years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Every four years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every five years"}]},{"question":"People from which country played a significant role in the building of the Canadian Pacific Railway?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"China"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Great Britain"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Italy"}]},{"question":"Who was General Sir Arthur Currie?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The most famous explorer of western Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The greatest military leader of the M tis"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The greatest Canadian soldier in the First World War"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The person who started the 'Marathon of Hope'"}]},{"question":"In which industry do most Canadians work?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manufacturing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Information Technology"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Service"}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of the term 'Premier'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier is the title given to the head of government of the Municipality of Toronto."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Premier is the title given to the head of government of a Canadian province or territory."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier is the title given to the Queen's representative in Canada."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier is the title given to the head of government of the country of Canada."}]},{"question":"Who is considered by many to be the father of Manitoba?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Dr. Emily Stowe"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Louis Riel"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gabriel Dumont"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"John Graves Simcoe"}]},{"question":"Which oceans line Canada's frontiers?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Pacific Ocean and the Atlantic Ocean"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Arctic Ocean and the Pacific Ocean"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Pacific Ocean, the Atlantic Ocean, and the Arctic Ocean"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Atlantic Ocean, the Indian Ocean, and the Pacific Ocean"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are the three founding peoples of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Americans, the French, and the British"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Aboriginals, the French, and the British"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The British, the Americans, and the Aboriginals"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The French, the Americans, and the Indians"}]},{"question":"Who is the head of the government in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commissioner"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Queen Elizabeth II"}]},{"question":"The Municipal Government is responsible for which of the following?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Garbage removal"}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of the national motto, the Latin phrase, 'A Mari Usque Ad Mare'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"From sea to sea"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The rule of law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National pride"}]}],[{"question":"In World War II, Canada contributed more to the air efforts of the Allied nations than any other Commonwealth country. What did they provide?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"120 000 Fighter Planes"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"130 000 Allied aircrew, trained in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"180 000 Aircraft Parts"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"100 000 Bombers"}]},{"question":"When did Canada's economy and industry experience a boom?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the 1840s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the 1860s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the 1880s"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In the 1890s and early 1900s"}]},{"question":"Who appoints the judges of the Supreme Court of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commissioner"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Governor General"}]},{"question":"What is the minimum age for voting in federal, provincial, territorial, and municipal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"16"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"21"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"18"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"19"}]},{"question":"Who was the first person to draw a map of Canada's eastern coast?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jean Talon"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"John Cabot"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jacques Cartier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Count Frontenac"}]},{"question":"What is a name by which the highest trial court of a province can be called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Small Claims Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Court"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Court of Queen's Bench"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Supreme Court of Canada"}]},{"question":"Who built the French Empire in North America?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pierre Le Moyne and Sieur d'Iberville"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Jean Talon, Bishop Laval, and Count Frontenac"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"King Charles II"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Great Britain"}]},{"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of the Dominion of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir John Alexander Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir George-Étienne Cartier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Leonard Tilley"}]},{"question":"Which province is Canada's largest producer of hydroelectricity?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland & Labrador"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the industrial and manufacturing heartland of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prairie Provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northern territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"West Coast"}]},{"question":"Where do the majority of Canadians live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the Prairie Provinces"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"On the West Coast"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the Northern territories"}]},{"question":"Who recommended that Upper and Lower Canada be merged and given a sole responsible government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir George-Étienne Cartier"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Lord Durham"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Leonard Tilley"}]},{"question":"Who is the Queen's representative in Canadian provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A Senator"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Lieutenant-Governor"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A member of the Legislative Assembly"}]},{"question":"Why is there a border between Canada and the USA?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To prevent war between the two countries"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To indicate that Canada and the United States are two separate countries"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To improve security"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To maintain distance"}]},{"question":"Who has the right to run for a post in federal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Any Canadian citizen who is at least 18 years old"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Any Canadian citizen 16 years of age or older"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Anyone"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Any man who is at least 18 years old"}]},{"question":"Postwar Canada became a more flexible and open society. Which of the following was this based on?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Equality of men and women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inequality of women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Equality of men"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inequality of men and women"}]},{"question":"What is \"due process\"?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the impartial manner in which the laws are administered"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the legal requirement that the government must respect all the legal rights that are owed to each person."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the rule of law and freedom under the law"}]},{"question":"What are the three main types of industries in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources, tourism, and service industries"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Tourism, service industries, and manufacturing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources, tourism, and information technologies (IT)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Natural resources, manufacturing, and service industries"}]},{"question":"What are the main functions of the Cabinet?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To prepare the budget and propose new laws to be implemented"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Navigation"}]},{"question":"Which province in Canada is the smallest by land size?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland & Labrador"}]},{"question":"What do electors need to have with them at a polling station in order to vote in an election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A ballot paper"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Proof of identity, and proof of address"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A valid credit card"}]},{"question":"What is the last line of our National Anthem?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"O Canada, we stand on guard for thee!"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"God keep our land glorious and free!"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada! Our home and native land!"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The true North strong and free!"}]},{"question":"When did the British North America Act come into effect?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1871"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1905"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1898"}]},{"question":"Who circled the globe in a wheelchair to raise funds for spinal cord research?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gerhard Herzberg"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Rick Hansen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Reginald Fessenden"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Terry Fox"}]},{"question":"For which of the following are municipal governments responsible?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal Affairs"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Snow removal"}]}],[{"question":"Which one of the following governments provides 'publicly-funded' education?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Provincial and territorial governments"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Municipal government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal government"}]},{"question":"For which of the following is the Municipal Government responsible?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal Affairs"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Urban transit"}]},{"question":"What is the first language of more than three-quarters of the population of Quebec?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"French"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"German"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Italian"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English"}]},{"question":"When did \"Canada\" become the official name of the land?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1773"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1758"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1791"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1799"}]},{"question":"What are members of the House of Commons also known as?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Senators"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Members of Parliament or MPs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"}]},{"question":"The provinces are responsible for which of the following?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Navigation"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Health care"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"}]},{"question":"When people need a representative to act on their behalf in a court of law, who should they hire?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A Politician"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A Member of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A lawyer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A police officer"}]},{"question":"When did Canada's first financial institutions open?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In the late 18th and early 19th centuries"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the early 18th century"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the early 16th century"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the late 19th century"}]},{"question":"Who was Sir George-Étienne Cartier?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada's first Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first head of a responsible government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first French-Canadian Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A railway lawyer and famous politician"}]},{"question":"Which of the following songs is Canada's national anthem?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"O Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Maple Leaf Rag"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"My Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Maple Leaf Forever"}]},{"question":"The Great Lakes are all located in which Canadian Province?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Michigan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Huron"}]},{"question":"What is the usual tenure of the Governor General of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"7 years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"5 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"4 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"6 years"}]},{"question":"Which country is Canada's largest trading partner?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"India"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Japan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"China"}]},{"question":"Where have most immigrants come from since the 1970s?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"England"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Asia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"USA"}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of the right to a secret ballot?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It means that voters have the right to vote in secret and the right to keep their voting decisions secret."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It means that voters have the right to vote in secret after telling the polling officer which candidates they want to elect."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It means that voters have the right to take the ballot paper out of the polling station and put it in a secret place."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"}]},{"question":"What do the symbols on the coats of arms on Canadian bills represent?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All of these"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Scotland and Ireland"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red maple leaves"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"England and France"}]},{"question":"Which of the following people were Loyalists?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Army commanders"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal peoples"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"People loyal to the Crown"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British colonialists"}]},{"question":"How is the Prime Minister of Canada appointed?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The leader of the party with the most elected representatives becomes the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister is chosen by the Members of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister is chosen by the Members of Provincial Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister is chosen by the Senate"}]},{"question":"Which of the following was a key phrase in the British North America Act of 1867 (Canada's original constitutional document)?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Geopolitical Entities"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Peace, Order, and Good Government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Trade and Communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Discipline, Education, and Good Public Order"}]},{"question":"What are the colors on the Canadian Flag?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Red and white"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Green and white"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Blue and white"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red and blue"}]},{"question":"What is the name of the national police force of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Royal Canadian Military Police (RCMP)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The South East Mounted Police (SEMP)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The North West Mounted Police (NWMP)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP)"}]},{"question":"What are the three levels of government in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal, state, and city"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal, provincial or territorial, and county"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Federal, provincial or territorial, and municipal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal, provincial or territorial, and rural"}]},{"question":"If the government loses a confidence vote in the assembly, they:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Do nothing"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Must resign"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Continue to govern without confidence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Call for by-elections"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are four distinct regions in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northern Territories, Prairies, Arctic and Pacific"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northern, Atlantic, Eastern, Pacific"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prairies, Pacific, Atlantic and Western"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Western, Central, Atlantic and Northern"}]},{"question":"When is Remembrance Day in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 1st"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"November 1st"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"November 11th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"September 7th"}]}],[{"question":"Which of the following represents protecting and enjoying heritage and environment in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Equality rights"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Citizenship responsibilities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Laws of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Government responsibilities"}]},{"question":"Today, diversity enriches the lives of Canadians. Where is diversity most seen?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the Canadian countryside"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Canadian towns"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the Rocky Mountains"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In Canadian cities"}]},{"question":"In 1980, Terry Fox began a cross-country run, the 'Marathon of Hope.' What was its purpose?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To raise funds for cancer research"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To raise funds for heart research"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To raise funds for clinical research"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To raise funds for spinal cord research"}]},{"question":"What are the parties that are not in power called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Candidates"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Without power"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Opposition parties"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Out of power"}]},{"question":"Who started the Marathon of Hope?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"James Naismith"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Terry Fox"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Sam Steele"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rick Hansen"}]},{"question":"What is the highest medal of honor presented to Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canada Cross"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Victoria Cross"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen's Medal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Medal"}]},{"question":"Which is the most popular spectator sport of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Hockey"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Cricket"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basketball"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Soccer"}]},{"question":"How many judges serve in the Supreme Court of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"7"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"9"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"10"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"5"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians were killed in World War I, from 1914-1918?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"70 000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"200 000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"170 000"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"60 000"}]},{"question":"Who elects members to the House of Commons in Ottawa, and to the provincial and territorial legislatures?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The people"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Government employees"}]},{"question":"When were female Canadian citizens over the age of 21 granted the right to vote in federal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1933"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1918"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1818"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1928"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a responsibility of the provincial government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Natural resources"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians have been awarded the Victoria Cross?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"2"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1222"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"96"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"500"}]},{"question":"What was the main trade of the first companies formed in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The fish trade"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The timber trade"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The fur trade"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The gold trade"}]},{"question":"Who, among these, is a Nobel Prize-winning Canadian scientist?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Gerhard Herzberg"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Harold Innis"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Marshall McLuhan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"}]},{"question":"Which is the largest religious affiliation in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Roman Catholicism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hinduism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Judaism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Muslim"}]},{"question":"How many provinces and territories does Canada have?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"10 provinces and 3 territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"10 provinces and 2 territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"9 provinces and 3 territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"3 provinces and 10 territories"}]},{"question":"For how long was the title \"Dominion of Canada\" officially used?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"250 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"200 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"50 years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"100 years"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of the federal government of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Local transit systems"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"National Defence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of municipal governments?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Local health and social services"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"}]},{"question":"How does a bill become the law in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Once a majority of Members of Parliament and Senators have approved a bill, the Governor General gives the final approval and then the bill becomes law."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A bill becomes the law after two readings in the House of Commons."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General approves all bills and they become the law after two debates."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A bill becomes the law after it has passed four readings in the House of Commons and Senate."}]},{"question":"Traditionally, how often are Members of Parliament elected?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every three years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every five years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Every four years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every two years"}]},{"question":"Who is considered Canada's greatest soldier?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"General Sir Arthur Currie"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Phil Edwards"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rick Hansen"}]},{"question":"Where do the majority of Francophones live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's system of political governance called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Benevolent dictatorship"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Parliamentary government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Democratic process"}]}],[{"question":"Which province is connected to Canada's mainland by one of the longest continuous multi-span bridges in the world?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Vancouver Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland & Labrador"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prince Edward Island"}]},{"question":"Which was the first province in the British Empire to move towards the abolition of slavery?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lower Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Southern Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northern Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Upper Canada"}]},{"question":"What can Canadians do if they cannot pay for a lawyer?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They can petition a politician"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They can call the police"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They can apply for Legal Aid Services"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They can write a letter to their Member of Parliament"}]},{"question":"Who invented the Cardiac pacemaker?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Dr. John A. Hopps"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gabriel Dumont"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward"}]},{"question":"What was the Women's Suffrage Movement?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"An effort by women to achieve the right to vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"An effort by women to achieve the right to a seat in Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"An effort by women to achieve the right to work"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"An effort by women to achieve the right fight in the military"}]},{"question":"Which country was liberated by the Canadian Army in 1944 - 1945?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Netherlands"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Japan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Austria"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Germany"}]},{"question":"How are Senators selected?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are selected by the Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are appointed on the advice of the Governor General."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They are appointed on the advice of the Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are elected by the people."}]},{"question":"At the Olympic Games in 1996, which Canadian became a world record sprinter and double Olympic gold medalist?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"John Cabot"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Wayne Gretzky"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Donovan Bailey"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Fontaine"}]},{"question":"What is the capital of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Toronto"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ottawa"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hamilton"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"London"}]},{"question":"Jurisdiction is shared by federal government and provinces over which of the following sectors?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Agriculture and Immigration"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial trade and communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence and health"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"}]},{"question":"When is Canada day? What is celebrated on this day?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"July 1st, when the anniversary of Confederation is celebrated each year"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"May 21st, when the Queen's birthday is celebrated each year"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"June 24th, when multiculturalism is celebrated each year"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 4th, when the anniversary of Confederation is celebrated each year"}]},{"question":"Who suggested the name 'Dominion of Canada' in 1864?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John Alexander Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lord Elgin"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Leonard Tilley"}]},{"question":"Which are the two official languages of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Italian and French"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English and Chinese"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English and Italian"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"English and French"}]},{"question":"When electors vote, they are required by law to reveal their choice to the following:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Elections Canada officials"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No one"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Their employer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The police"}]},{"question":"When is Remembrance Day celebrated?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 1st"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"November 11th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"May 1st"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"December 26th"}]},{"question":"Which bill contains Sir Wilfrid Laurier's portrait?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The $10 bill"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The $50 bill"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The $5 bill"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The $20 bill"}]},{"question":"What makes a jury?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A group of impartial citizens"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A group of lawyers"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A group of judges"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A group of people who know the law"}]},{"question":"What is significant about the number of people living in Ontario?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They make up half of all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They make up three-fourths of all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They make up one-third of all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They make up two-thirds of all Canadians"}]},{"question":"What was significant about the Canadian navy at the end of the Second World War?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It was the third-largest navy in world."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the second-largest navy in world."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the fourth-largest navy in world."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the largest navy in world."}]},{"question":"What is the name of the Royal Anthem of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"I Affirm"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"God Save the Queen (or King)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"I Swear"}]},{"question":"Which of these is a Canadian icon comprised of serving members of the Canadian Armed Forces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Lieutenant Governor and his Cabinet"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Royal Canadian Navy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor Generals"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Snowbirds"}]},{"question":"In what year were the Aboriginal Peoples granted the right to vote?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1950"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1960"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1790"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1632"}]},{"question":"Who do you call the Queen's representative in the provinces and territories?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Senator"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Lieutenant-Governor"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier"}]},{"question":"Who are the ancestors of the Métis?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Europeans and Americans"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Aboriginals and Europeans"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Americans and Aboriginals"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inuit and Aboriginals"}]},{"question":"What does the term \"mobility rights\" mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to work at home"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The right to live and work anywhere in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to freedom of speech"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to be given a job in any province"}]}],[{"question":"How many Canadians served in World War II?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"More than 1 000 000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 400 000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About  1000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"More than 5 000 000"}]},{"question":"Which level of government passes \"by-laws\"?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Municipal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Provincial"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"State"}]},{"question":"What do people promise when they take the Oath of Citizenship?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They pledge to fulfill the duties of a Canadian citizen and they pledge allegiance to the Queen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They pledge to observe the laws of Canada and they pledge to fulfill the duties of a Canadian citizen"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They pledge allegiance to the Queen, they pledge to observe the laws of Canada, and they pledge to fulfill the duties of a Canadian citizen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They pledge allegiance to the Queen and they pledge to observe the laws of Canada"}]},{"question":"Where are the Parliament Buildings located?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In Ottawa"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Hull"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Quebec City"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Toronto"}]},{"question":"What are the three parts of the Canadian Parliament?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister, the House of Commons, and the Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister, the Premiers, and the House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen, the Governor General, and the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Queen, the House of Commons, and the Senate"}]},{"question":"Where do the English and French have equal status in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In Quebec"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In the Parliament of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the workplace"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"At City Hall"}]},{"question":"What is the population of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"39 million"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"35 million"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"21 million"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"17 million"}]},{"question":"In what year did Canada become an independent country?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1967"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1872"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1776"}]},{"question":"Which province has a long history of coal mining, forestry, and agriculture?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"}]},{"question":"How many electoral districts are there in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"115"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"21"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"135"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"308"}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of the Remembrance Day poppy?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To celebrate Confederation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To honour Prime Ministers who have died"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To remember the Sovereign, Queen Elizabeth II"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day"}]},{"question":"In Canada, are voters obliged to tell others how they voted?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"If a family member would like to know how they voted, yes"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"If the Lieutenant Governor asks, yes"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"If a Member of Parliament asks, yes"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No, but they may choose to discuss how they voted with others"}]},{"question":"What are four legal rights of citizenship of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The right to be educated in either official language, the right to vote, the right to apply for a Canadian passport, and the right to enter and leave Canada freely"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to have a job, the right to vote,  the right to drive, and the right to go to school"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to go to school, the right to work, the right to have a bank account, and the right to travel"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to travel, the right to live anywhere, the right to work anywhere, and the right to get married"}]},{"question":"What is a major river in Quebec?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Niagara River"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Hudson's Bay"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Fraser River"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The St. Lawrence River"}]},{"question":"Which courts are for civil cases involving small sums of money?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Small Claims Courts"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Provincial Courts"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Trial Courts"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Court"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of the municipal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal Affairs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Firefighting"}]},{"question":"Where does the name \"Canada\" come from?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From 'kanata', the Métis word meaning ‘rivers'"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"From \"kanata\", the Huron-Iroquois word for village"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From 'cantata', the Inuit word meaning ‘country'"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From 'Canadienne', the French word meaning ‘joining'"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the oldest colony of the British Empire in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Newfoundland & Labrador"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"}]},{"question":"In what way do electors mark their choice on a federal election ballot?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By putting \"-\" in the circle beside the name of their chosen candidate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By writing the name of their chosen candidate on the ballot"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By writing \"YES\" in the circle beside the name of their chosen candidate"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"By putting \"X\" in the circle beside the name of their chosen candidate"}]},{"question":"Who is the federal representative of Canada's Monarch?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister's spouse"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Governor General of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"All applicants are required to provide proof of English or French language skills to become a Canadian citizen with the exception of the following:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Adult applicants 40 years of age and over"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Adult applicants 50 years of age and over"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Adult applicants 65 years of age and over"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Adult applicants 55 years of age and over"}]},{"question":"Who is Canada's Head of State?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Senate"}]},{"question":"What are the Prime Minister and Cabinet Ministers together called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Cabinet"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Government"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the responsibility of the provincial governments?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"}]},{"question":"Which is the most famous invention of Research In Motion (RIM), a wireless communications company?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Blackberry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first electronic voice message"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The iPhone"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadarm"}]}],[{"question":"What is the final step before a bill becomes a law?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Approved by the King (or Queen)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Approved by the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Approved by the Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Approved by a judge"}]},{"question":"Which of the following answers is NOT true about the Canada/USA relationship?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada and the USA share the longest undefended international border"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada and the USA are the largest trading partners in the world"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada exports very few goods to the USA"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canada/USA relationship is the closest and most extensive in the world"}]},{"question":"Which region covers more than one-third of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Northern Territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Southern Region"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northern Region"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Southern Territories"}]},{"question":"What is the name of the Royal Anthem of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Great Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"God Save the Queen (or King)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Oh Canada"}]},{"question":"What is a minority government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The party in power holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party in power holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons and the Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party in power holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party in power holds at least half of the seats in the Senate"}]},{"question":"What is written on an election ballot?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The names of the candidates in your election district"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Who you should vote for"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The date and time you are allowed to vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Where you should vote"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are the responsibilities of the provincial government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Education, health care, natural resources, and policing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defense, health care, citizenship, and firefighting"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education, foreign policy, natural resources, and policing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defense, foreign policy, highways, and aboriginal affairs"}]},{"question":"Which province has the most bilingual Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"}]},{"question":"Which province is one of the most productive agricultural regions in the world?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Saskatchewan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"}]},{"question":"When is Canada Day?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"November 5th every year"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"July 1st every year"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"June 30th every year"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 31st every year"}]},{"question":"What does 'mobility rights' mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Being able to use any mobile phone service in Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Being able to live and work anywhere in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Being able to live and fish anywhere in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Being able to play hockey anywhere in Canada"}]},{"question":"Who is Canada's Head of State?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier of Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"What is the Okanagan Valley famous for?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Coal mines"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lakes and fishing"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Fruit orchards"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sunrises and sunsets"}]},{"question":"In what year did Canada become a country?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1687"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1786"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1678"}]},{"question":"What are the two official languages of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inuktitut and English"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French and Inuktitut"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"English and French"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mandarin and English"}]},{"question":"What do you call the Queen's (or King's) representative in the provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Governor-Lieutenant"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Queen's (or King's) Governor"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Lieutenant-Governor"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Governor General"}]},{"question":"How are Members of Parliament chosen?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Elected by senators"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Elected by the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Chosen by the Queen (or King)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Elected by Canadian citizens"}]},{"question":"Which Act granted, for the first time in Canada, legislative assemblies elected by the people?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Constitutional Act of 1982"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Constitutional Act of 1891"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Constitutional Act of 1791"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Constitutional Act of 1972"}]},{"question":"Who appoints the judges of the Supreme Court of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Other judges"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The people"}]},{"question":"A Canadian citizen has the right to ____ in federal elections.","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Know how to register as a voter"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Be a candidate"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All of the above"}]}],[{"question":"Which region is known as the industrial and manufacturing heartland of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Atlantic Provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prairie Provinces"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"West Coast"}]},{"question":"What does it mean to say that Canada is a constitutional monarchy?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign (King or Queen) must approve bills before they become law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign (King or Queen) represents Canadians in Parliament"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada's Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (King or Queen) who reigns in accordance with the Constitution"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign (King or Queen) is the lawmaker of Canada"}]},{"question":"When is Remembrance Day celebrated?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 1"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"October 6"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"November 11"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"November 20"}]},{"question":"What are the provinces of Central Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario and Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec and New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta and Saskatchewan"}]},{"question":"Where do the majority of Métis people live in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The North"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prairie Provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Maritimes"}]},{"question":"Who is Canada's largest trading partner?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The United Arab Emirates"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The United States of America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The United Kingdom"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mexico"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are responsibilities of Canadian citizens?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Protecting the Canadian environment and voting in elections"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Obeying the law, finding work in the government, and serving in the Canadian army"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Serving in the Canadian army, obeying the law, and taking responsibility for oneself and one's family"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Obeying the law, serving on a jury, voting in elections, and helping others in the community"}]},{"question":"Which region of Canada is known for its fertile agricultural land and energy resources?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prairie Provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Maritime Provinces"}]},{"question":"True or False? In 1813, Government House and the Parliament Buildings were accidentally burned.","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"True"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"False"}]},{"question":"Which province in Canada is the smallest by land area?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"}]},{"question":"Who was the first person to draw a map of Canada's east coast?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jean Talon"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Georges Cartier"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"John Cabot"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jacques Cartier"}]},{"question":"Who is exempt from the language requirement for Canadian citizenship?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Anyone who does not live in a major city"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Anyone who does not want to take the test"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Any adult applicant who is 55 years of age or older"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Any adult applicant who is 55 years of age or younger"}]},{"question":"Which three minerals are still mined in the territories today?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Lead, gold, and zinc"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Silver, lead, and zinc"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Zinc, gold, and bronze"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Zinc, lead, and aluminum"}]},{"question":"What are the first two lines of Canada's national anthem?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada! True patriot love in all thy sons command"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada! Our home and native land! True patriot love in all thy sons demand"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada! We stand on guard for thee"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"O Canada! Our home and native land! True patriot love in all thy sons command"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are responsibilities of local government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education, foreign policy, and transportation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health care, natural resources, and transportation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defense, health care, and transportation"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Social and community health, snow removal, and transportation"}]},{"question":"What does the Canadian flag look like?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red with a white maple leaf"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red and white with a bear"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"White with a red border on each end and a red maple leaf in the center"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red and white with provincial emblems"}]},{"question":"What is a major river in Quebec?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hudson Bay"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Niagara River"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fraser River"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"St. Lawrence River"}]},{"question":"Which legal documents protect the rights of Canadians regarding official languages?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada Constitution and Official Languages Act"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadian Constitution and Official Languages Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian Languages Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian Official Languages Act"}]},{"question":"Who circled the globe in a wheelchair to raise funds for spinal cord research?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Reginald Fessenden"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Rick Hansen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Terry Fox"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gerhard Herzberg"}]},{"question":"Who is known as the 'Father of Manitoba' and a defender of Métis rights?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Louis Riel"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir William Riel"}]}],[{"question":"Which of the following is a non-Canadian NOT allowed to do?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Leave the country at will"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Contact their Member of Parliament (MP)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Take the Canadian citizenship test"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Vote in federal and provincial elections"}]},{"question":"Why is the North sometimes called the 'Land of the Midnight Sun'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is closer to the sun."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The northern lights appear at midnight."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is nighttime most of the year."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Summer daylight can last up to 24 hours."}]},{"question":"One-third of all Canadians live in which province?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Saskatchewan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Who has the right to ask you whom you voted for?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No one."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Any other Canadian."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Your local MP."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister."}]},{"question":"Who was the first leader of a responsible government in Canada in 1849?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Louis Riel"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alec Baldwin"}]},{"question":"Who are Francophones?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"People who speak French as their first language."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who come from France."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who are learning French."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who speak French as their second language."}]},{"question":"Who recommended merging Upper and Lower Canada and giving them responsible government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Guy Carleton"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Lord Durham"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir George-Étienne Cartier"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians served in World War II?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"More than one million"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fewer than 500,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 900,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 500,000"}]},{"question":"Who has the right to enter and leave Canada freely?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prisoners"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of the Commonwealth"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadian citizens"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Job seekers"}]},{"question":"What is the capital city of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ottawa"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Victoria"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Toronto"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Who has the right to apply for a Canadian passport?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prisoners"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadian citizens"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of the Commonwealth"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Permanent residents who are job seekers"}]},{"question":"Who were the 'Group of Seven' in Canadian history?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A group of influential politicians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A group of famous Canadian explorers"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada's first Olympic athletes"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A group of artists who painted Canadian landscapes"}]},{"question":"What does 'responsible government' mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The government must answer to the King or Queen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The government must follow international law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The government must be transparent with citizens"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The government must resign if defeated in a non-confidence vote"}]},{"question":"What was the main outcome and significance of the War of 1812 for Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada became part of the United States"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It established Canada's first parliament"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It ensured Canada remained independent from the United States"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It ended British rule in Canada"}]},{"question":"Which level of government in Canada passes laws known as 'by-laws'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Provincial government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Municipal governments"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Territorial governments"}]},{"question":"What does Canada's national motto, 'A Mari Usque Ad Mare,' mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From sea to shining sea"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From land to sea"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From coast to coast"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"From sea to sea"}]},{"question":"What are the three key characteristics of Canada's system of government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal monarchy, constitutional democracy, parliamentary state"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Federal state, parliamentary democracy, constitutional monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal republic, parliamentary democracy, constitutional monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal republic, democratic parliament, constitutional government"}]},{"question":"Which industry did many early Canadian companies engage in?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Fur trade"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Agriculture"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fishing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Logging"}]},{"question":"Who selects Cabinet Ministers in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Voters in federal elections"}]},{"question":"Who are the Acadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English-speaking refugees who settled in Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Descendants of French colonists who settled in the Maritime provinces beginning in 1604"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People originally from the Acadia region in France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who primarily speak French as their second language"}]}],[{"question":"Who can ask the Governor General to call an early federal election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Supreme Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The King or Queen"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"Who are the Aboriginal peoples of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first settlers of Newfoundland"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first European settlers to arrive in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The descendants of the first Australian immigrants to Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The first inhabitants of Canada"}]},{"question":"Which province is Canada's largest producer of pulp and paper?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Saskatchewan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"What should you do if you don't receive a voter information card before an election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Call your local municipality"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Go to your nearest polling station on election day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Assume you were not chosen to vote"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Contact Elections Canada"}]},{"question":"What are political parties that are not in power called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Tea parties"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Opposition parties"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rival parties"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Opponent parties"}]},{"question":"How is the Prime Minister chosen?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of Parliament vote to select the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General and the Senate appoint the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The King or Queen appoints the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The leader of the party with the most elected Members of Parliament becomes Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"Which region is known as the 'Land of the Midnight Sun'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Northern Territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prairies"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Maritimes"}]},{"question":"Why is British Columbia known as Canada's Pacific Gateway?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Because billions of dollars in goods are shipped to and from Asia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Because it borders the Pacific Ocean"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Because many people of Asian origin live there"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Because it attracts tourists year-round"}]},{"question":"When was the Magna Carta signed?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1649"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1215"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1425"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1615"}]},{"question":"What right is included in the Great Charter of Freedoms?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal peoples' rights"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Employment rights"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Freedom of conscience and religion"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom from taxes"}]},{"question":"What does \"Habeas corpus\" mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to live and work anywhere in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to peaceful assembly"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to speak freely"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The right to challenge unlawful detention by the state"}]},{"question":"When was the Constitution of Canada amended to include the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1902"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1859"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1982"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1949"}]},{"question":"Who proclaimed the amended Constitution of Canada in 1982?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Senate"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Queen Elizabeth II"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The people of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"What are the two principles upon which Canada is founded?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The supremacy of God and the rule of law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The supremacy of God and freedom of speech"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The supremacy of law and the rule of God"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mobility rights and the rule of law"}]},{"question":"With which words does the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms begin?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"Canadian citizens have rights and responsibilities\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"O Canada! Our home and native land!\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"Canada is a free country and home of the brave\""},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"\"Whereas Canada is founded upon principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law\""}]},{"question":"Who can freely enter and leave Canada without time constraints?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian citizens and landed immigrants"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Commonwealth citizens"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadian citizens"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British citizens"}]},{"question":"Which three rights are included in the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom of expression rights, property rights, and fair trial rights"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Mobility rights, Aboriginal Peoples' rights, and official language rights"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal Peoples' rights, voting rights, and official language rights"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Employment rights, mobility rights, and freedom rights"}]},{"question":"Canadians work hard to respect:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Marxism"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Pluralism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Capitalism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Individualism"}]},{"question":"What is a fundamental characteristic of Canadian heritage and identity?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Maple syrup"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Multiculturalism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Habeas corpus"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hockey"}]},{"question":"When called upon, serving on a jury is:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Optional"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A legal requirement"}]}],[{"question":"There is no compulsory military service in Canada.","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"True"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"False"}]},{"question":"What is considered a noble way to contribute to Canada and an excellent career choice?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Serve in the regular Canadian Forces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Serve on a jury"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Belong to a union"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Learn both official languages"}]},{"question":"What is the 'Great Charter of Freedoms' also known as?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Habeas Corpus"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Dominion of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian Constitution"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Magna Carta"}]},{"question":"How have poets and songwriters described Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"Peace, Order, and Good Government\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The \"Great Outdoors\""},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The \"Great Dominion\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The \"Land of the Brave\""}]},{"question":"When did the name \"Canada\" begin appearing on maps?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By the 1750s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By the 1580s"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"By the 1550s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By the 1650s"}]},{"question":"When was Canada's first representative assembly elected?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1791"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1758"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1889"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1609"}]},{"question":"Who chose Ottawa as Canada's capital?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Queen Elizabeth I"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Queen Elizabeth II"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Queen Victoria"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Queen Anne"}]},{"question":"When was Canada's current flag raised for the first time?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1921"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1965"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1949"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1892"}]},{"question":"How much of Canada's exports are destined for the U.S.A.?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Over one-third (1/3)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Over three-quarters (3/4)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Over two-thirds (2/3)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Over half (1/2)"}]},{"question":"Who was known as \"the greatest living Canadian\"?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Dr. Wilder Penfield"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Terry Fox"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Sandford Fleming"}]},{"question":"In which Act are the responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments defined?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Government Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Responsibilities Act"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Constitution Act"}]},{"question":"Which phrase embodied the vision for the Dominion of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"The land of the strong and free\""},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"\"Dominion from sea to sea and from the river to the ends of the earth\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"Dominion from ocean to ocean\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"Oh Canada, my home and native land\""}]},{"question":"Where are the Great Lakes located?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Atlantic Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Between Ontario and the United States"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northern Quebec"}]},{"question":"What is the difference between the role of the Sovereign and that of the Prime Minister?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign links Canada to 52 other nations, and the Prime Minister is the guardian of constitutional freedoms."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign is the symbol of Canadian sovereignty, and the Prime Minister is her aide."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign is the Head of State, and the Prime Minister oversees provincial policies."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Sovereign is the guardian of constitutional freedoms, and the Prime Minister selects Cabinet Ministers and is responsible for government operations and policies."}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of the Remembrance Day poppy?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To remember our Sovereign, Queen Elizabeth II."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To honour Prime Ministers who have died."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To celebrate Confederation."}]},{"question":"Who was General Sir Arthur Currie?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada's greatest soldier in the First World War."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A great frontier hero."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"An explorer of western Canada."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A military leader of the Métis in the 19th century."}]},{"question":"What are the territories of Northern Canada and their capital cities?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Yukon Territory (Whitehorse), Northwest Territories (Yellowknife), and Nunavut (Iqaluit)."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northwest Territories (Yellowknife) and Alaska (Juneau)."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northwest Territories (Yellowknife)."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alaska (Juneau) and Yukon Territory (Whitehorse)."}]},{"question":"When must federal elections be held?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Whenever the Prime Minister calls an election."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About every four years."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"When MPs want a new Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"On the third Monday in October every four years following the most recent general election."}]},{"question":"What does the term \"responsible government\" mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The ministers of the Crown must have the support of a majority of elected representatives to govern."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Each person in each electoral district is responsible for voting."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General is responsible for the actions of the Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All Canadians are responsible for each other."}]},{"question":"How many electoral districts are there in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"178"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"20"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"308"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"99"}]}],[{"question":"Where do most French-speaking Canadians live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Which party becomes the Official Opposition?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party selected by the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party receiving the fewest votes"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The party with the second-most votes"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Any independent candidate"}]},{"question":"A Member of Parliament from Montreal announces that she will spend her weekend in her electoral district. This means she will be:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In her office on Parliament Hill"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In the part of Montreal where she was elected"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Visiting the province of Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Going on vacation"}]},{"question":"How is the government formed after a federal election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Each province elects one representative to form the government. The Queen (or King) then chooses the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General selects a party and a Prime Minister to run the government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The party with the most elected representatives becomes the governing party. The leader of this party becomes the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party with the most elected representatives becomes the governing party. The Queen (or King) chooses the Prime Minister from this party"}]},{"question":"What was the significance of the June 6, 1944, invasion of Normandy?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadians made a significant contribution to the defeat of Nazism and Fascism in Europe during the Second World War"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It liberated North Africa from Nazi occupation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It resulted in the forcible relocation of Canadians of Japanese origin"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It led to the establishment of the Juno Awards"}]},{"question":"Which three oceans border Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hudson, Pacific, and Atlantic"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Atlantic, Arctic, and Bering"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pacific, Indian, and Atlantic"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Atlantic, Arctic, and Pacific"}]},{"question":"After a federal election, which party forms the new government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The party with the most elected representatives becomes the governing party."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen (or King) selects a party to run the government."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premiers of each province select a party to run the government."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General proposes a law allowing elected officials to form the government."}]},{"question":"Who played an important role in building the Canadian Pacific Railway (CPR)?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Acadian railroad workers."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"African-American slaves."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"American railroad engineers."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Chinese railroad workers."}]},{"question":"In Canada, are you required to tell others how you voted?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Yes, if your family asks."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Yes, if your Member of Parliament asks."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No, but you may choose to discuss how you voted with others."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Yes, if the Lieutenant Governor asks."}]},{"question":"Which provinces are connected to Ontario by land?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Manitoba and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba and Alberta"}]},{"question":"Who do Canadians vote for in a federal election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A candidate they want to represent them in Parliament."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All candidates in their electoral district."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The best speaker running an election campaign."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Someone to become the Premier of the province."}]},{"question":"When is Canada's fixed federal election date?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The third Friday in September every four years after the most recent election"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"There is no fixed date for Canada's federal election"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"March 3rd every five years after the last election"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The third Monday in October every four years after the most recent election"}]},{"question":"Who do Members of Parliament represent?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Everyone who lives in their electoral district"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Everyone who lives in their neighbourhood"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Everyone who lives in their province"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Everyone in Northern Canada"}]},{"question":"Which group of people played an important role in building the Canadian Pacific Railway?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Chinese"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Indians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English"}]},{"question":"How are Senators chosen?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By the Premier of all provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"By the Governor General of Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Appointed by the King or Queen"}]},{"question":"What is the role of opposition parties?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To ensure reports about the current government are sent to the King or Queen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To supervise the government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To oppose or try to improve government proposals"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To regulate government proposals"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are responsibilities of the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"National defence, foreign policy, international trade, and Aboriginal affairs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defence, health care, international trade, and Aboriginal affairs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways, policing, international trade, and criminal justice"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education, foreign policy, recycling programs, and Aboriginal affairs"}]},{"question":"In what year was Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1687"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1876"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1786"}]},{"question":"What song is Canada's national anthem?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"God Save the King or Queen"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"O Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Oh Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Great Canada"}]},{"question":"What is the trial court sometimes called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Civil Court"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Court of King's or Queen's Bench"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Small Claims Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Supreme Court"}]}],[{"question":"On what date did Nunavut become a territory?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"April 1, 1999"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"May 1, 1998"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 1, 1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"July 31, 1820"}]},{"question":"Why is the British North America Act important in Canadian history?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was agreed to by the First Nations and Inuit"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was written by the British government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Aboriginal people signed the act"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It made Confederation legal"}]},{"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir John Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pierre Elliote Trudeau"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pierre Elliott Trudeau"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John McDonald"}]},{"question":"Which animal is an official symbol of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The bear"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The moose"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The beaver"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The snowbird"}]},{"question":"What is an electoral district?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A geographical area where politicians reside"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"An area where politicians work"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A geographical area represented by a member of the House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The area where voting takes place in your locality"}]},{"question":"What part of the Constitution legally protects the basic rights and freedoms of Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canada Charter of Responsibilities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canada Charter of Rights and Freedoms"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Charter of Rights and Free will"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's best-known symbol and national police force?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"RMCP"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"CIA"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian Police"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"RCMP"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of the Quebec Act of 1774?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It allowed Quebec to gain independence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It allowed the French to move into Quebec"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada's tolerance of religious traditions under the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It gave the French more power"}]},{"question":"Which province is on the Pacific coast of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"British Columbia"}]},{"question":"Which province is recognized as the birthplace of Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Who are Anglophones?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who were taught English at school"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who understand but do not speak English"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People who do not speak English as a first language"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"People who speak English as a first language"}]},{"question":"Which group of Aboriginal peoples has the largest population in the Northwest Territories and Nunavut?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Acadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Métis"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"First Nations"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Inuit"}]},{"question":"During World War II, in which aspect did Canada contribute more to the Allied air effort than any other Commonwealth country?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Trained 130,000 Allied aircrew"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Deployed paratroopers in France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Provided ammunition"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sent 130,000 soldiers to reclaim France from Germany"}]},{"question":"How can a party in power be defeated in Parliament?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"If there is a revolution"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"If the Queen (or King) orders the party to resign"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"If a majority of MPs vote against a major government decision"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"If a minority of MPs vote against a major government decision"}]},{"question":"Where are the Parliament Buildings located?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Toronto"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Kingston"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"London"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ottawa"}]},{"question":"Which court deals with matters concerning the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A provincial court"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Federal Court of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A family court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A traffic court"}]},{"question":"In which year was oil discovered in Alberta, marking the beginning of Canada's modern energy industry?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1947"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1951"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1965"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1970"}]},{"question":"Who are the Métis?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"First Nations people who speak the Michif dialect"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The distinct Aboriginal people of Atlantic Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A distinct people of mixed Aboriginal and European ancestry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"People of mixed Inuit and First Nations ancestry, most of whom live on the Prairies"}]},{"question":"What do you mark on a federal election ballot?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A checkmark"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"An 'X'"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A sticker"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A thumbprint"}]},{"question":"What does the Register of Electors contain?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A list of all Canadian citizens who are qualified to vote in federal elections and referendums"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A list of people who are willing to vote in elections and referendums"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A list of people who voted for the opposition party in the previous election"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A list of people who are not allowed to vote"}]}],[{"question":"Thousands of slaves escaped from the United States by following the North Star north to Canada.","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"True"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"False"}]},{"question":"When did the United Empire Loyalists come to Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Late 1600s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Early 1600s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Early 1700s"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Late 1700s"}]},{"question":"What happens when the federal government loses a confidence vote?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The government must resign, and an election is held"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The official opposition party takes power"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister loses his job"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister is no longer the leader of his party"}]},{"question":"Which countries fought in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Britain and Germany"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Britain and France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"France and China"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"America and Britain"}]},{"question":"When did the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms become part of the Constitution?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1892"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1872"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1982"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1782"}]},{"question":"When did thousands of miners first come to Yukon?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1870s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1980s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1780s"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1890s"}]},{"question":"When is Sir Wilfrid Laurier Day celebrated?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"12th of November"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"20th of November"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"22nd of November"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"2nd of November"}]},{"question":"Which group of Aboriginal peoples has the largest population in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Acadians"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"First Nations"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Indians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Metis"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of the Canadian discovery of insulin?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It saved the lives of sick children"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It saved millions of lives of people with diabetes"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It helped in the treatment of heart diseases"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was an important medicine for saving soldiers' lives during World War II"}]},{"question":"Which legal document recognizes the cultural diversity of Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Charter of Freedoms"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Multicultural Act of the United Nations"}]},{"question":"What is the title of the federal representative who fulfills ceremonial and executive duties in Canada's three territories?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Commissioner"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Member of the Legislative Assembly"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"\"Sir\""},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lieutenant-Governor"}]},{"question":"Which Act ensures common elements and a basic standard of coverage in Canadian healthcare?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Canada Health Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Official Languages Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Old Age Security Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The British North America Act"}]},{"question":"What are the provinces of the Atlantic region?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, Prince Edward Island and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Nova Scotia, Newfoundland, New Brunswick and Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick, Nova Scotia, Ontario and Quebec"}]},{"question":"What is the effort by women to achieve the right to vote known as?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The suffrage motion of women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The women's voting law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The election law"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The women's suffrage movement"}]},{"question":"How are Canada's three territories different from its provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They have exactly the same status as provinces but have smaller populations"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They do not have the status of provinces, but have governments and assemblies that carry out many of the same functions"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They have no elected assemblies"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are represented by a Premier chosen by the Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"Who were the United Empire Loyalists?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inuit and First Nations"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French and British settlers"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"First Nations and British settlers"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Settlers from the United States during the American Revolution"}]},{"question":"Why is the Battle of Vimy Ridge important in Canadian history?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the last battle of the First World War"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It has come to symbolize Canada's coming of age as a nation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was an important victory in the Boer War"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Out of it was formed the Canadian Corps"}]},{"question":"Which province has the most valuable forest industry in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"British Columbia"}]},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the sport of lacrosse?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The official winter sport"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The second most popular sport in Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The official summer sport"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The most popular sport in Canada"}]},{"question":"What do you call a law before it is passed?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A proposed law"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A bill"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A new law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A proposal of a law"}]}],[{"question":"Where does the name \"Canada\" come from?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From the Inuit word \"Kanata,\" meaning nations"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"From \"Kanata,\" the First Nations word for village"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From the Inuit word meaning home"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"From the First Nations word meaning land"}]},{"question":"At what age must Senators retire from the Senate?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"70"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"65"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"75"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"80"}]},{"question":"What form of transportation did Aboriginal peoples and fur traders use?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Waterways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Railways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Roads"}]},{"question":"On what principle was Canada's constitution founded?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Independence and freedom"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Liberty, equality, and fraternity"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Liberty and pursuit of freedom"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Peace, Order, and Good Government"}]},{"question":"What is the most popular spectator sport in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Soccer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian football"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Hockey"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basketball"}]},{"question":"What are the three main groups of Aboriginal peoples?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Métis, Inuit, and United Empire Loyalists"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Acadians, Métis, and First Nations"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Early French settlers, Métis, and Indians"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Métis, First Nations, and Inuit"}]},{"question":"What are the three main types of industries in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Natural resources, manufacturing, and services"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mining, services, and manufacturing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Oil, tourism, and manufacturing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fishery, tourism, and services"}]},{"question":"Which country lies on Canada's southern border?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Central America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mexico"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Michigan"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"United States of America"}]},{"question":"What are the Prairie provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Saskatchewan and Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta, Manitoba, and British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Saskatchewan, Alberta, and Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Saskatchewan and Alberta"}]},{"question":"In the Canadian justice system, what are the roles of the courts and the police?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The courts make laws and the police enforce them"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The courts enforce federal laws and the police enforce provincial laws"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The courts enforce laws and the police settle disputes"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The courts settle disputes and the police enforce laws"}]},{"question":"What is a majority government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party in power holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons and the Senate"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The party in power holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party in power holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The party in power holds at least half of the seats in the Senate"}]},{"question":"Which countries fought in the War of 1812?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"United Kingdom and United States of America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"France and United Kingdom"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada and United States of America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"France, Great Britain, and United States of America"}]},{"question":"What is the tower in the centre of the Parliament buildings called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Peace Tower"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada Tower"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Peaceful Tower"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"CN Tower"}]},{"question":"Name three requirements you must meet in order to vote in a federal election.","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian citizen, at least 21 years old, and on the list of electors"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadian citizen, at least 18 years old, and on the voters' list"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Working for the government, at least 21 years old, and Canadian citizen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian citizen, at least 16 years old, and on the voters' list"}]},{"question":"Which two provinces are on the Atlantic coast of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia and Yukon"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Nova Scotia and New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland and British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island and Ontario"}]},{"question":"What is a Voter Information Card?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A list that tells you who the candidates are in your electoral district"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A letter that lets you know the voting schedule"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A form that tells you where and when to vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A card that lets you register for voting"}]},{"question":"More than half of Canada's aeronautics and space industry is located in which province?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Saskatchewan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"}]},{"question":"How many provinces and territories are there in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Eight provinces and three territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ten provinces and two territories"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nine provinces and two territories"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ten provinces and three territories"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians served in the First World War?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 170,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 10,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"More than 60,000"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"More than 600,000"}]},{"question":"Which group of leading industrialized countries is Canada a part of?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"G2"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"G4"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"G8"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"NATO"}]}],[{"question":"When did the British North America Act come into effect?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1881"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1901"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1876"}]},{"question":"What does \"official language rights and minority language educational rights\" mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English is more important than French in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French is more important in Quebec, and English is more important in other provinces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All languages have equal status in Canada's government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"French and English have equal status in Parliament and throughout the government"}]},{"question":"Which UNESCO World Heritage Site in Canada contains the remains of a Viking settlement from about 1,000 years ago?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"L'Anse aux Meadows"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Port Royal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gros Morne National Park"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Penticton Valley"}]},{"question":"Who built the French Empire in North America?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"King Charles II"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Jean Talon, Bishop Laval, and Count Frontenac"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pierre Le Moyne, Sieur Iberville"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Great Britain"}]},{"question":"Which province is Canada's leading wheat producer?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Saskatchewan"}]},{"question":"In Canada's justice system, what does \"presumption of innocence\" mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister can determine who is innocent in court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Everybody is guilty until proven innocent"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Everyone is innocent until proven guilty"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The judge can determine who is guilty without evidence"}]},{"question":"What important trade did the Hudson's Bay Company control?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gold"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Oil"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fishery"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Fur"}]},{"question":"When does a federal election have to be held under legislation passed by Parliament?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"When the Queen (or King) wants to replace the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Within 4 years of the most recent election"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Within 5 years of the last election"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister can call the election anytime at his own will"}]},{"question":"Which city provides important shipping and air links across the Pacific Ocean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Victoria"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Calgary"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Edmonton"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Vancouver"}]},{"question":"What is Terry Fox's contribution?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"He inspired people to contribute money for cancer research"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"He was the greatest hockey player in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"His discovery of insulin saves millions of people's lives"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"He was a brilliant soldier"}]},{"question":"What is the highest honour available to Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen's Medal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Elizabeth Cross"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Victoria Medal"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Victoria Cross"}]},{"question":"What are the regions of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"West, North, South, East, Central"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"West Coast, Central, East, Canadian Shield and South"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Atlantic, North, Central, Prairies and West Coast"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rockies, Ontario, Quebec, Prairies"}]},{"question":"What does Confederation mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The joining of provinces to become a new country"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The United States Confederate army came to settle in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The combination of neighborhoods to build a larger community"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The merger of colonies to form a province"}]},{"question":"Which natural resource industries have played an important role in Canada's history and development?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Forestry, fishing, agriculture, mining and energy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Automobiles, aerospace and finance"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Tourism, government and retail services"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All of the above"}]},{"question":"In which period did Canada's economy and industry experience a boom?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1880s"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1890s and early 1900s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1920s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1860s"}]},{"question":"In which year did the British Parliament abolish slavery throughout the Empire?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1807"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1793"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1833"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1847"}]},{"question":"Which ocean is Newfoundland closest to?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Atlantic"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pacific"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Labrador Sea"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Arctic"}]},{"question":"What document made Confederation legal?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Immigration Act"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The British North America Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Citizenship Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Charter of Rights and Freedoms"}]},{"question":"From whom are the Acadians descended?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Métis and Inuit"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"First Nations who began settling in what are now the Prairie provinces in the 1600s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"French colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604"}]},{"question":"What are the three parts of Parliament?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen (or King), Governor General and Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General, the Legislative Assembly and the Senate"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Queen (or King), the House of Commons and the Senate"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The House of Commons, the Legislative Assembly and the Senate"}]}],[{"question":"Which two are Great Lakes?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"St Lawrence and Superior"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario and Okanagan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Michigan and Okanagan"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Huron and Erie"}]},{"question":"In which type of jobs do most Canadians work?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Service"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lumbering"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Farming"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"}]},{"question":"Which province is the only officially bilingual province?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"New Brunswick"}]},{"question":"What does voting by secret ballot mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"No one can watch you vote except the election officer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The voter should not tell anyone whom they voted for"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Only the candidate you vote for can watch your marked ballot"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No one can watch you vote or look at your marked ballot"}]},{"question":"Which province is Canada's largest producer of hydroelectricity?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"}]},{"question":"Which territory shares a border with another country?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northwest Territories"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Yukon Territory"}]},{"question":"Which two fundamental freedoms are protected by the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Freedom of belief and freedom of religion"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Equal employment rights and opportunities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basic living rights and obedience to laws"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Aboriginal peoples' rights and volunteering"}]},{"question":"What do the initials MP stand for in Canadian politics?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Member of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Minister of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Member of the Patriots"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Master of the Province"}]},{"question":"Which was the last province to join Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Newfoundland"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Yukon"}]},{"question":"Where do most French-speaking Canadians live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"}]},{"question":"Which four provinces first formed Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario, Quebec, Nova Scotia and New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario, Newfoundland, Quebec and Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and British Columbia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario, Quebec, Manitoba and Nova Scotia"}]},{"question":"When was the Canadian Pacific Railway completed?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Late 1600s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Late 1700s"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Late 1800s"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Early 1700s"}]},{"question":"Who has the right to run as a candidate in federal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Any man who is at least 18 years old"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Any Canadian citizen who is at least 18 years old"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian citizens and landed immigrants"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A Canadian citizen who is 16 years or older"}]},{"question":"What are the territories of northern Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nunavut and Yukon Territory"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Northwest Territories and Alaska"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Yukon and Northwest Territories"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Yukon Territory, Northwest Territories and Nunavut"}]},{"question":"What is the population of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 32 million"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 36 million"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"About 34 million (Discover Canada says 34 million, while the most recent data says 41 million, as of Jan 2025)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"About 40 million"}]},{"question":"How does a bill become a law?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The governors of each province must approve the bill"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It must be approved by a majority in the House of Commons and Senate, and receive royal assent"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It must be signed by the Queen or King"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It must be approved by Members of Parliament"}]},{"question":"What will you promise when you take the Oath of Citizenship?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Carry out responsibilities as a Canadian citizen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pledge allegiance to the Queen (or King)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Promise to obey the Constitution of Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Pledge loyalty to the Queen (or King), observe the laws, and fulfill the duties of a Canadian"}]},{"question":"What was the name of the new country formed during Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Britain"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian Confederation"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Dominion of Canada"}]},{"question":"Which statement best describes the role of the judicial branch of government in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are responsible for passing laws and monitoring expenditures"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They interpret and apply the law, ensuring it is consistent with the Constitution"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They represent the Sovereign in each province"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They form the Cabinet under the direction of the Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"What are the elected representatives at the provincial or territorial level usually called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of Parliament (MPs)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Cabinet Ministers"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Members of the Legislative Assembly (MLAs), Members of the National Assembly (MNAs), Members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs), or Members of the House of Assembly (MHAs)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Senators"}]}],[{"question":"Fatima is a new immigrant to Canada. Why is she allowed to choose any job, just like a man?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Because of equality between French and English"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Because she came from the United Kingdom"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Because of the equality of women and men in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Because she has a university degree"}]},{"question":"The Quebec Act of 1774:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Allowed religious freedom for Catholics"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Is one of the constitutional foundations of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Permitted Catholics to hold public office"}]},{"question":"In which UN operation did Canada participate from 1950 to 1953?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian Forces defended Hong Kong"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Corps captured Vimy Ridge"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada participated in the UN operation defending South Korea in the Korean War"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadians volunteered to fight in the South African War"}]},{"question":"What does equality under the law mean?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To be protected against any discrimination"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To be discriminated against"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To be like anyone else in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To be the same as anywhere in the world"}]},{"question":"What does it mean for a political party to \"be in power\"?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To gain the approval of the Queen (or King)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To have the most elected representatives"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To generate electricity"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To hold the nuclear button"}]},{"question":"Which two provinces produce more than three-quarters of Canada's manufactured goods?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec and Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia and Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta and Ontario"}]},{"question":"If you cannot pay for a lawyer, how can you get legal help?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Borrow money from the government and pay for the lawyer"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Go to legal aid services available in most communities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Apply for financial aid from the government to pay for legal fees"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Do not go to court"}]},{"question":"Where do more than half of the people in Canada live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Coastal Pacific"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Atlantic Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prairies"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Central Canada"}]},{"question":"What is a ballot?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A form that tells you when and where to vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A dance"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A form for voting"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A form to count the number of votes"}]},{"question":"What is a polling station?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Place where you vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Campaign offices for candidates"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Place where votes are counted"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Member of Parliament's constituency"}]},{"question":"What is a Cabinet Minister?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Candidate selected by the Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"MP chosen by the Premier of each province"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"MP selected by the Prime Minister to run federal departments"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"MP selected by the King or Queen to make laws"}]},{"question":"Who discovered insulin?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Dr. Wilder Penfield"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Matthew Evans and Henry Woodward"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Frederick Banting and Charles Best"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Dr. John A. Hopps"}]},{"question":"Who are the Quebecois?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All French-speaking people in Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"People who form a nation within a united Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Descendants of British settlers who live in Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadians who only speak French"}]},{"question":"Who invented the snowmobile?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Sandford Fleming"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Matthew Evans and Henry Woodward"}]},{"question":"What is the primary role of the police in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To resolve disputes and interpret laws"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To keep people safe and enforce the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To provide national security intelligence to the government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To conduct or support land warfare, peacekeeping, or humanitarian missions"}]},{"question":"Which of the following criteria gives a Canadian the right to vote?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Owning a house"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Being on the official voters list"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Having a driver's license"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Being an immigrant"}]},{"question":"Who among the following is above the law in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Judges"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Police"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No one"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Politicians"}]},{"question":"What does the Crown mean for Canadians?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A symbol of government, including Parliament, legislatures, courts, police services, and the armed forces"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It contains symbols of England, France, Scotland, and Ireland, as well as red maple leaves"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A national motto, 'A Mari Usque Ad Mare,' which in Latin means 'from sea to sea'"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A reflection of the Greco-Roman heritage of Western civilization in which democracy originated"}]},{"question":"What did the Suffrage Movement achieve?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec experienced an era of rapid change"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It abolished slavery in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It led to the introduction of employment insurance"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Women achieved the right to vote"}]},{"question":"Where did the first European settlers in Canada come from?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Germany"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"England"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Iceland"}]}],[{"question":"Which principles is Canada's constitution based on?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Multiculturalism, Peace, and Order"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Peace, Order, and Good Government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"War, Order, and Good Government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mobility Rights, Order, and Good Government"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of hockey in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the national summer sport"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of these"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the most popular spectator sport in Canada and also its national winter sport"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada won a gold medal in the 2008 Olympics in this event"}]},{"question":"Which religious community do the majority of Canadians belong to?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Christian"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jewish"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Muslim"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hindu"}]},{"question":"What are the three branches of the Canadian government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Executive, Senate, and Judicial"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Executive, Legislative, and Monarchy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Executive, Police, and Judicial"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Executive, Legislative, and Judicial"}]},{"question":"Under Canadian law, why is every person presumed innocent until proven guilty?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"No person or group is above the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Men and women are equal under the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom of thought, belief, opinion, and expression"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To guarantee due legal process under the law"}]},{"question":"Who governs Canada on a daily basis at the federal level?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Queen (or King)"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"Which Canadian province is the largest producer of oil and natural gas?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Alberta"}]},{"question":"What does the National Register of Electors contain?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A database of landed immigrants"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A database of Canadian citizens at least 18 years of age who are qualified to vote in federal elections and referendums"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A database of all Canadian citizens"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A database of Canadian taxpayers"}]},{"question":"What is the main advantage of the NAFTA agreement?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Free trade among Canada, the USA, and Mexico"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Free trade between Canada and China"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Free trade between Canada and the UK"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Free trade between Canada and Japan"}]},{"question":"Which northeastern Canadian province has its own time zone?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Newfoundland & Labrador"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"}]},{"question":"What is the voting procedure in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Whichever way you like"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Online"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Secret ballot"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Open ballot"}]},{"question":"What does the Canadian Crown symbolize?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A Mari Usque Ad Mare"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Symbols of England, France, Scotland, and Ireland"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"RCMP, the national police force, and one of Canada's best-known symbols"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada is a constitutional monarchy"}]},{"question":"Which Canadian province has the largest population?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"}]},{"question":"Who is awarded the Victoria Cross?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian politicians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Police officers"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Best innovation of the year"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A Canadian showing conspicuous bravery or self-sacrifice"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a responsibility of Canadian citizens?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Learning to speak both official languages"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Voting in elections"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Obeying the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Taking responsibility for oneself and one's family"}]},{"question":"What do Canadians remember on Remembrance Day?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian victory in World War I"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian victory in the Battle of Vimy Ridge"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian victory in World War II"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sacrifices made by Canadian veterans and brave soldiers in wars"}]},{"question":"Why was the Canadian Pacific Railway built?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To enable immigrants to settle in Central Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Because British Columbia joined Canada in 1871 after Ottawa promised to build a railway to the West Coast"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To provide a spectacular tourist excursion across precipitous passes and bridges"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"So British Columbia could handle the trade of goods worth billions of dollars worldwide"}]},{"question":"Why is trade with other countries important to Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Trade with other countries changed the native way of life forever"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To increase trade and enjoy one of the world's highest standards of living"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada has become a member of the World Trade Organization"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The French and Aboriginal people collaborated with Canada in the vast fur trade economy"}]},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the role of the Queen (or King) in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To make important decisions about how the country is governed"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To peacefully oppose or try to improve government proposals"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To run the federal government departments"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To focus on citizenship and allegiance, be a symbol of Canadian sovereignty, and serve as a guardian of constitutional freedoms"}]},{"question":"Federal elections are carried out to elect which of the following?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Member of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Senator"}]}],[{"question":"What is part of our heritage under the Canadian legal system?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All answers correct"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Freedom under law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Democratic principles and due process"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rule of law"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's largest city and main financial center?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Vancouver"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Toronto"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Montreal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Calgary"}]},{"question":"Which of the following describes two responsibilities of provincial or territorial governments?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Policing and citizenship"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Policing and firefighting"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defense and highways"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Education and health care"}]},{"question":"What do Canadians normally wear on Remembrance Day?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A red poppy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A green shirt"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A black tie"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A white shirt"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's best-known symbol?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Maple Leaf"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Beaver"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Fleur-de-lys"}]},{"question":"Where do Inuit people live?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Reserve land"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In scattered communities across the Arctic"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prairie Provinces"}]},{"question":"Who contributed to the invention of the radio and sent the world's first wireless voice message?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Reginald Fessenden"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mike Lazaridis"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mathew Evans"}]},{"question":"Which region was stormed and captured on D-Day (June 6, 1944) by the 3rd Canadian Infantry Division?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Berlin"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Juno Beach"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"London"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Paris"}]},{"question":"Who invented the sport of basketball?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Germans"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Americans"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a responsibility of the provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Municipal government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Navigation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial trade and communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"}]},{"question":"What are the men who established Canada called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Fathers of Confederation"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fathers of the Dominion of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fathers of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fathers of the Constitution"}]},{"question":"How long is the Lieutenant Governor appointed for?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"3 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"4 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"6 years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"5 years"}]},{"question":"Which of the following describes two responsibilities of the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"National defense and foreign policy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"National defense and firefighting"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Citizenship and maintaining highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health care and education"}]},{"question":"In which year did the British Parliament prohibit the buying and selling of slaves?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1793"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1877"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1807"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1833"}]},{"question":"Who became the first French-Canadian prime minister after the formation of Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John Alexander Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Wilfrid Laurier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir George-Étienne Cartier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Leonard Tilley"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a responsibility of the federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Health care"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"}]},{"question":"Which is a fundamental characteristic of Canadian heritage and identity?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Multiculturalism"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French culture"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canadian festivals"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English culture"}]},{"question":"When does Canada celebrate Thanksgiving?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The second Monday of October"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first Friday of October"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first Monday of September"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first Monday of July"}]},{"question":"Complete the sentence: The House of Commons is a representative committee ____","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"appointed on the advice of the prime minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"made up of Members of Parliament elected by the people"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"appointed on the advice of the governor general"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"made up of members selected by the prime minister"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the highest court in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A provincial court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The small claims courts"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Supreme Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Court"}]}],[{"question":"What is the symbol of the Canadian government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Parliament"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Crown"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The National Flag"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Snowbirds"}]},{"question":"Who represents an electoral district?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commissioner"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Lieutenant Governor"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A Member of Parliament"}]},{"question":"Which of the following was invented by Alexander Graham Bell?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"BlackBerry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fax Machine"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Telephone"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Internet"}]},{"question":"Which sport has the greatest number of registered players in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lacrosse"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Soccer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Curling"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basketball"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a responsibility of the provinces?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defence"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Foreign Policy"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Education"}]},{"question":"Which province has the largest population of Aboriginals?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Manitoba"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"}]},{"question":"How is Canada ranked in terms of geographical size in the world?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the second-largest country on Earth"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the smallest country on Earth"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the largest country on Earth"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the seventh-largest country on Earth"}]},{"question":"When is Labour Day celebrated in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 1st of July"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The 1st Monday of September"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 1st of May"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The 3rd Monday of October"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the federal government responsible for?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural Resources"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Education"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Interprovincial Trade and Communications"}]},{"question":"What is celebrated on April 9th?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Vimy Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Family Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Thanksgiving Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Boxing Day"}]},{"question":"When was employment insurance introduced by the Canadian federal government?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1947"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1950"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1940"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1965"}]},{"question":"What information can be found on a voter information card?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Confirms that your name is on the voters' list"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"States when you vote"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"States where you vote"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All answers correct"}]},{"question":"In the 1960s, Quebec experienced an era of rapid change. What was it called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The East Movement"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Quiet Revolution"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Suffrage Movement"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Francophonie"}]},{"question":"Who invented the worldwide system of standard time zones?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Reginald Fessenden"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Sandford Fleming"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"}]},{"question":"The ancestors of Aboriginal peoples are believed to have migrated from which continent?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Asia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Europe"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Australia"}]},{"question":"What is celebrated on December 26?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Remembrance Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Victoria Day"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Boxing Day"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada Day"}]},{"question":"Which statement best describes Canadian federalism?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All legislative power is centralized in Ottawa"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It forces each province to adopt the same policies as the federal government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It allows provinces to adopt policies tailored to their own populations and provides flexibility to experiment with new ideas"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Provinces have no authority or responsibilities and rely entirely on federal directives"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's national winter sport?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lacrosse"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Basketball"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Hockey"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Golf"}]},{"question":"What types of jobs are provided by service industries?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Communications and retail services"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Transportation and education"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All answers are correct"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Tourism and government"}]},{"question":"The municipal government is responsible for which of the following?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Currency"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Garbage removal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Highways"}]}],[{"question":"Which of the following are the three founding peoples of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"American, French, and British"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Aboriginal, French, and British"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French, American, and Indian"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British, American, and Aboriginal"}]},{"question":"Who is a Premier?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister is also called the Premier"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A Premier has a role similar to that of the Prime Minister in a federal government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commissioner"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Governor General"}]},{"question":"What is the meaning of the phrase 'the world's longest undefended border'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada exports billions of dollars worth of energy products to the USA"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada enjoys close relations with the United States"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Over three-quarters of Canadian exports are destined for the USA"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Millions of Canadians and Americans cross the border every year in safety"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of the sport lacrosse in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the most popular sport"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is the official winter sport"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is an ice game"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It is the official summer sport"}]},{"question":"How often are federal elections held?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every five years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every six years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Every seven years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Every four years"}]},{"question":"What does the blindfolded Lady Justice symbolize?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Blind to all considerations other than facts"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The government must respect all of the legal rights a person is entitled to under the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Our judicial system is founded on the presumption of innocence in criminal matters"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of these"}]},{"question":"To whom do we profess our loyalty in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Flag"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A person who represents all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Geopolitical entities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadian Constitution"}]},{"question":"Which oceans line Canada's frontiers?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Pacific Ocean in the west"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Atlantic Ocean in the east"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Arctic Ocean to the north"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All answers correct"}]},{"question":"Who is the head of government in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Sovereign"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commissioner"}]},{"question":"What is the last line of the National Anthem?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"God keep our land glorious and free"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The true North strong and free"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"O Canada! Our home and native land"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"O Canada, we stand on guard for thee"}]},{"question":"What is 'due process'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The government must respect all the legal rights a person is entitled to under the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The rule of law and freedom under the law"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The impartial manner in which the laws are administered"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of these"}]},{"question":"What do we need to bring with us to vote?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of these"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Voter information card, voter identity, and proof of address"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Credit card"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ballot paper"}]},{"question":"What is the reason behind the Canada-U.S. border?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To improve security"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To maintain distance"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Canada wishes to remain independent of the United States"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"To prevent war between the two countries"}]},{"question":"What is another name for a trial court?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Court of Queen's Bench"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Provincial Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Small Claims Court"}]},{"question":"What is the minimum voting age for federal, provincial, territorial, and municipal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"18"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"19"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"21"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"16"}]},{"question":"What are the main functions of the Cabinet?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Navigation"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"To prepare the budget and propose new laws"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defense"}]},{"question":"After the war, Canada became a more flexible and open society. What was this based on?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Equality of men and women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inequality of women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inequality of men and women"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Equality of men"}]},{"question":"The arms that appear on dollar bills contain symbols of what?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All answers correct"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Scotland and Ireland"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"England and France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red maple leaves"}]},{"question":"What are the members of the House of Commons also known as?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Commissioners"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Members of Parliament or MPs"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of these"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs)"}]},{"question":"What are the colors of the Canadian flag?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Blue and white"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Red and white"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Green and white"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Red and blue"}]}],[{"question":"Who was Sir George-Étienne Cartier?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A railway lawyer and Montrealer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first French-Canadian prime minister"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first head of a responsible government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Canada's first prime minister"}]},{"question":"Who among the following can help you with legal problems?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Politicians"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Lawyers"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Members of Parliament"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The police"}]},{"question":"How many Great Lakes are located between Ontario and the United States?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Five"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Four"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Seven"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Six"}]},{"question":"If the government loses a confidence vote in the assembly, they:","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Call for by-elections"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Can continue"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Do nothing"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Must resign"}]},{"question":"What is the tenure of the Governor General?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"4 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"6 years"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"5 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"7 years"}]},{"question":"Which of the following are distinct regions included in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prairie Provinces and the West Coast"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Atlantic Provinces, Ontario, and Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Northern Territories"}]},{"question":"Who were the Loyalists?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"People loyal to the Crown"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The commanders of armies"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British colonists"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Indigenous peoples"}]},{"question":"Where have most immigrants come from since the 1970s?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Asia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"England"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"France"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"USA"}]},{"question":"Which level of government provides publicly funded education?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"City government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Provincial and territorial governments"}]},{"question":"When was Canada's first financial institution opened?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Early 16th century"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Late 19th century"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Late 18th and early 19th centuries"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Early 18th century"}]},{"question":"Which of the following was a key phrase in the British North America Act, Canada's original constitutional document of 1867?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Geopolitical entity"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Trade and communications"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Peace, Order, and Good Government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Discipline, education, and good public"}]},{"question":"More than three-quarters of the population in Quebec speak which language?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French as a second language"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"French as a first language"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"German as a first language"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"English as a first language"}]},{"question":"Who are the national police force of Canada and one of its best-known symbols today?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The South East Mounted Police"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Military Police"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The North West Mounted Police"}]},{"question":"When did 'Canada' become the official name of the country?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1799"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1773"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1791"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1758"}]},{"question":"What are the three levels of government in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal, provincial, and county"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal, state, and city"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Federal, provincial or territorial, and municipal"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Federal, provincial, and rural"}]},{"question":"For what product did the first companies formed in Canada compete?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Timber trade"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gold trade"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Fur trade"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fish trade"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians were killed in World War I, from 1914 to 1918?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"60,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"170,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"200,000"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"70,000"}]},{"question":"When were female Canadian citizens over the age of 21 granted the right to vote in federal elections?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1933"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1928"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1818"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1918"}]},{"question":"Who elects the members of the House of Commons in Ottawa and the provincial and territorial legislatures?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Government employees"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The people"}]},{"question":"Traditionally, Members of Parliament are elected by the people after how many years?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Four years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Three years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Five years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Two years"}]}],[{"question":"For how long was the title 'Dominion of Canada' officially used?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"100 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"250 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"50 years"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"200 years"}]},{"question":"How many judges serve on the Supreme Court of Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"7"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"9"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"10"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"5"}]},{"question":"What is Canada's system of political governance called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Monarchy"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Parliamentary government"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Democratic process"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Benevolent dictatorship"}]},{"question":"Which of the following best represents protecting and enjoying Canada's heritage and environment?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Government responsibilities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Citizenship responsibilities and the laws of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Laws of Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Citizenship responsibilities"}]},{"question":"Who started the 'Marathon of Hope'?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rick Hansen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"James Naismith"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir Sam Steele"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Terry Fox"}]},{"question":"Who is considered Canada's greatest soldier?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"General Sir Arthur Currie"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Phil Edwards"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Rick Hansen"}]},{"question":"What is the largest religious affiliation in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Roman Catholic"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Hindu"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Muslim"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Jewish"}]},{"question":"Who among these is a Nobel Prize-winning scientist?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Gerhard Herzberg"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Marshall McLuhan"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Harold Innis"}]},{"question":"How many Canadians have been awarded the Victoria Cross?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"96"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"500"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"2"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1222"}]},{"question":"Where is diversity most reflected in Canada today?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Countryside areas"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Cities"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Towns"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mountains"}]},{"question":"Jurisdiction is shared by the federal government and provinces over which of the following sectors?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Agriculture and immigration"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Interprovincial trade and communications"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Defense and health"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Natural resources"}]},{"question":"In what year were Aboriginal Peoples granted the right to vote?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1960"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1790"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1950"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1632"}]},{"question":"Which country was liberated by the Canadian Army in 1944–1945?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Germany"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Austria"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Netherlands"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Japan"}]},{"question":"Who suggested the name 'Dominion of Canada' in 1864?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir Leonard Tilley"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lord Elgin"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Sir John Alexander Macdonald"}]},{"question":"What was significant about the Canadian Navy at the end of the Second World War?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It was the third-largest navy in the world"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the fourth-largest navy in the world"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the largest navy in the world"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It was the second-largest navy in the world"}]},{"question":"Which is the most famous invention of Research In Motion (RIM), a wireless communications company?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Canadarm"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first wireless voice message"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The BlackBerry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The iPhone"}]},{"question":"The Métis people are a mixture of which ancestries?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Aboriginal and European ancestry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"European and American ancestry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"American and Indian ancestry"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Inuit and Indian ancestry"}]},{"question":"In 1996, at the Olympic Games, which Canadian became a world record sprinter and double Olympic gold medalist?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Wayne Gretzky"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"La Fontaine"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Donovan Bailey"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"John Cabot"}]},{"question":"Which was the first province in the British Empire to move toward the abolition of slavery?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"South Canada"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Upper Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"North America"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Lower Canada"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is considered a Canadian icon?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The National Flag"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Crown"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Snowbirds"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Arms"}]}],[{"question":"Which province is connected to mainland Canada by one of the longest continuous multi-span bridges in the world?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland and Labrador"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Who invented the Cardiac pacemaker?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Gabriel Dumont"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Dr John A. Hopps"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Graham Bell"}]},{"question":"What is significant about the number of people living in Ontario?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They make up two-thirds of all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They make up three-fourths of all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They make up one-third of all Canadians"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They make up half of all Canadians"}]},{"question":"Which of the following is the oldest colony of British Empire in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alberta"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Newfoundland and Labrador"}]},{"question":"Who is the Queen (or King)'s representative in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Premier"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister's spouse"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Governor General of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Prime Minister"}]},{"question":"Which of the following lists contains four rights that Canadians have?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to go to school, to work, to have a bank account, and to travel"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The right to be educated in either official language, to vote, to apply for a Canadian passport, and to enter and leave Canada freely"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to travel, to live anywhere, to work anywhere, and to get married"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The right to have a job, to vote, to drive, and to go to school"}]},{"question":"Which courts are for civil cases involving small sums of money?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Small Claims Courts"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A Trial Court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A provincial court"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Federal Court"}]},{"question":"What are the Prime Minister and Cabinet Ministers together called?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Government"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Cabinet"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The House of Commons"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Senate"}]},{"question":"When asked, who must you tell who you voted for in a federal election?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A police officer"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"No one"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Your employer"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"An Elections Canada official"}]},{"question":"Where do the English and French have equal status in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In the workplace"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"In schools"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"In the Parliament of Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"At the City Hall"}]},{"question":"Which province has a long history of coal mining, forestry, and agriculture?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"New Brunswick"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"}]},{"question":"Where are the Parliament Buildings located?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Calgary"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Quebec City"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Ottawa"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Toronto"}]},{"question":"Who were the first people living in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"American and British"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Spanish"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"French and Chinese"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Indians (First Nations) and Inuits (Eskimos)"}]},{"question":"The natives (Aboriginal People) developed ____ .","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Language and culture"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Dancing and cleaning"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Singing and cooking"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Card games"}]},{"question":"Who were the first people of invent the kayak and the snowshoes?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The French and English"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Chinese and French"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Natives and the American"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Spanish and Japanese"}]},{"question":"Where did the first people settled?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario and Newfoundland"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British Columbia and Alberta"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec and Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Toronto"}]},{"question":"Which symbol was revived at Confederation and included in the Canadian Red Ensign?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Maple Leaf"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The Fleur-de-lys"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Beaver"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Union Jack"}]},{"question":"Which of the following people is the Father of Confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Stephen Harper"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Pierre Trudeau"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Alexander Mackenzie"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Sir John A. Macdonald"}]},{"question":"Who was Mary Ann Shadd Cary?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"An outspoken activist in the movement to abolish slavery in the U.S. and the first woman publisher in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The first woman to serve as a Member of Parliament in Canada"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A pioneering female officer in the North West Mounted Police (NWMP)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A French-Canadian hero of the War of 1812"}]},{"question":"Which international military alliance did Canada join with other western democracies during the Cold War?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"The North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Warsaw Pact"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The United Nations (UN)"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"The Commonwealth"}]}],[{"question":"When did Newfoundland and Labrador  join confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"None of the above"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1940"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1949"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1931"}]},{"question":"When did Northwest Territories join confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1870, July 15th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1870, July 4th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1875, July 15th"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1890, July 15th"}]},{"question":"When did British Columbia join confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1850"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1851"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1860"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1871"}]},{"question":"When did Prince Edward Island join confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1875"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1870"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1874"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1873"}]},{"question":"When did Yukon Territory join confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1898"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1979"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1891"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1930"}]},{"question":"When did Alberta join confederation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1875"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1905"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1850"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1840"}]},{"question":"Which province is known for having the world's highest tides in the Bay of Fundy?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Prince Edward Island"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ontario"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Nova Scotia"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Newfoundland and Labrador"}]},{"question":"In what jobs did the Metis first work with European Settlers?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Supplies, traders, guides and interpreters"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Taking care of children"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Building housing"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Fishing"}]},{"question":"What did the government do to make immigration to Western Canada easier?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Use the Great Lakes and seaway to prairies."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Built a railway across the prairies."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Built a highway across the prairies."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A and C"}]},{"question":"When and what city did settlers from France first establish on the St. Lawrence river?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Toronto in the early 1600's"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Montreal in the early 1600's"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Vancouver in the early 1600's"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Quebec City in the early 1600's"}]},{"question":"What is the significance of the Peace Arch at Blaine, Washington?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It symbolizes the long history of conflict between Canada and the United States."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It is a memorial for soldiers who fought in World War II."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"It symbolizes the close ties and common interests between Canada and the United States."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"It marks the border between Canada and Mexico."}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements best describes Canada's stance on barbaric cultural practices such as spousal abuse, forced marriage, honour killings, or female genital mutilation?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are permitted in remote areas of Canada with local consent."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are personal matters not covered by Canadian law."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"They are severely punished under Canada's criminal laws."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"They are tolerated if they are part of someone's cultural background."}]},{"question":"Which one is the duty of the Governor General?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"He/she selects the Prime Minister."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"He/she is responsible for the defense of the country."},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"After an election, he/she invites the party who has the most votes to form the new government."},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"He/she manages the federal budget."}]},{"question":"When was the official Language Act passed? (French and English)","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"1969"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1867"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"1982"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"2000"}]},{"question":"What does B.N.A. stand for?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"British National Alliance"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"British North American Act"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Black Nation Alliance"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Bank of National Association"}]},{"question":"How many members are there in the House of Commons?","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"338"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"310"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"270"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"295"}]},{"question":"How many levels of government are there in Canada?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Ten"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Five"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Thirteen"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Three"}]},{"question":"How are laws passed?","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Signed by the Governor General"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Read by the House of Commons three times"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Read by the Senate three times"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"All of the above"}]},{"question":"Every bill or proposed law must be approved by ____ and the Senate before it becomes law.","answer":[{"isCorrect":false,"text":"A citizen"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Queen Elizabeth II"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"All of the above"},{"isCorrect":true,"text":"A majority of members in the House of Commons"}]},{"question":"Each bill is presented ____ times for debate and discussion before given to the senate.","answer":[{"isCorrect":true,"text":"Three"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"One"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Two"},{"isCorrect":false,"text":"Four"}]}]]